We're in the
milk part, part 3/5 of the spoon,
you see, tell me what the first part
is?
Second,
the socket to the squirrel for yourself
again, I repeat, you
can try to continuously do that,
simply, it won't work, it will
even make your life complicated,
it won't work if
you only care about yourself,
it won't accomplish anything, and
you'll never find the
younger version of yourself or the older version of yourself.
But it's called looking for Trump. Meaning
it will never, never work
if you only focus on
what you want,
it will fail.
Third,
those are the good things when you
truly take
care of
yourself, your best friend, and others.
My teacher once said
you have to take care of all living beings, and you
are a living being, don't
think that it has to be you and them, it's
not, it's not the name of the
game.  The name of the game is that
everyone has the same equal rights.
You also have the same
equal right to experience happiness.
It's called "
Buddha, Buddha, Buddha, hurt yourself," meaning if you hurt
me, hurt
yourself, then hurt
others to make them happy. That's a
crazy idea; you'll definitely give
up. So, there has to be
equality and caring for
everyone, including you. I have some
Buddhist friends who don't
know how to take care of themselves. They
overdo it and overdo it, and they give up
or get sick and can't
continue.
You have to take care of yourself.
You have to be healthy, you have to be
healthy. If you ca
n't, you can't take care of others.
We'll move on to the text. I
like the Tibetan part.
Don't worry, you can ignore it, and
I'm planting seeds for next time. So
you don't need to learn Tibetan; just
try to pick up a few words.  That
means
when Sena, this simple line,
we taught in Kyoto a week
ago,
we visited a
[music]
story of King Shizuka.
So my brother, he's 72 years old, he
has a project in Montana that
he's working on, and they cut wood for
the poor. They have groups,
a group
like that, they like to bring
big tools and then chop everything up,
and they cut firewood once a week
for the poor, for the people
who
also have fireplaces. It's the
perfect picture of what they do with
stricina
or the bodies, half of them, and on
that day they also use that,
offering 50% of their bodies.
That story is about
offering the part that can be given,
and the deity allows the people, the
poor people, to
choose
50/50, and we found
that story in Kyoto, basically because of
the desire of  The intention of the day was to
share his body 50/50.
His body was restored,
and he was much happier and better.
We stopped,
we stopped, and we just released
a single line throughout the entire retreat. It was
very confusing. Not because we
realized that it would
take us a thousand years to finish learning
everything, but because the story was
incredibly beautiful, so we translated the whole
thing. It was readily available, you can
read it however you want. It's an
incredibly beautiful story,
and it fits perfectly in Kyoto.
We chose that city over
Kyoto and Tokyo because Kyoto
was
abandoned after the
Tang Dynasty. When the Tang Dynasty
flourished in China,
that city was left behind, and that's
where Buddhism began to spread
in China.
Kyoto, because of that culture, is the
last Tang Dynasty city in the
world. It has more Chinese people
than other cities.  In China, on my side, there are a
lot of Chinese people who come there to see, there
are about 70,000 temples, there are so
many in that city,
it's a
Buddhist city, very beautiful. If you have
the chance to go, the program in Kyoto is
extremely easy, almost for all countries,
and it's wonderful,
the people are very gentle, the climate is
very beautiful. We were there when the
cherry blossoms bloomed two weeks ago,
and
all the women and
people, for 20 years, had the opportunity to wear
kimonos, and I don't know
what the men's kimonos are called,
but it looked very magnificent
in that city, where they celebrate the
cherry blossoms.
Imagine the whole country is
very excited about the cherry blossom season,
and everyone is
like how
Americans are excited about bowling,
it's very fun.  That's great!
If that's it, and that's a great place
to learn. There will be
many programs there, and the
new groups welcome, whether small or
large, you can make small groups to see how it suits you
better.
We've already lowered the line there. And
now, our hearts will continue.
We will start with
an example of other people
who have made a similar sacrifice to be able to
care
for the needs of others. How funny is that?
And this is the part we're at,
the third part. When we go
through this part, we'll be ready to
start
swapping ourselves and others.
Talking about
a Bodhisattva,
a video shining on the head. They
cut it off. It's like an
offering to others. Sofia, the
jewel that grows naturally
on the head, on the head of a Bodhisattva.
Next,
this is a very famous storyline.
People ask me, Extra,
how do we start?  A historical story.
I remember it was around
1991 or '92. I was in New
York.
There were some people from
another Kagu tradition, a middle-level lineage.
You guys asked me, there
was a group of about 20 of them, and they asked me to teach them
Tibetan because they were going to be
doing it over the next year.
Their lama required them to read stories and
prayers in
Tibetan, and they asked me to teach them Tibetan.
So I thought, 'Oh, since
it's a different tradition, I
should teach them the scriptures.' Because the scriptures are
accepted by all the traditions, and no one would be
bothered if I taught the scriptures. So I
came and translated a scripture,
a national book of Mongolia, and
the stories there are called "data," meaning "
common joy," meaning "
suffering," about a tigress,
meaning giving her body to find
her own body. And that story is about
a great Bodhisattva called Ningzong.
In Tibetan,
it's the Great Bodhisattva and Mahasa. He is
Maha, but his personal name is
also Mahasapa,
which is Mahasapa. Mahasapa, in the Great Path, is
courageous. He
passed by a
hungry and sick tiger that
couldn't eat. It had four
cubs, four
of them, struggling to survive. They were lying down,
but they were suffering because they had no milk.
When you saw them, they were already
dead. The way it's written in the
Lamborghini is very interesting. He
says, "
Ola, Sang Nghi Hoa
Vu Lan," meaning
because it was hopeless, because
it was about to punish itself by eating its own cubs. It was
almost as if it was about to eat one, but in a
situation where, to save one
cub, it had to eat the
others. I've never seen it written like that before.
I saw it written in that
way, but it's very close
to the idea of ​​it eating
one of its own cubs so it could suckle milk.  He
took care of the remaining cubs,
and Mahasa stopped and decided
to give it his body.
He lay down beside it,
took off his shirt, and told it to eat.
It said it couldn't eat because it was weak.
There was a tree nearby, and he cut the
image of the tree. He couldn't. Every day, he
bared his chest, which was full of blood. Then he
lay down and let the tiger
lick his blood,
giving it his body.
When he died, he said, "Here
we have an agreement. If
you eat my flesh now,
when I become a Buddha, you
must be my first disciple. You
must be my first student."
Then he passed away, and it had a
healthy body and could feed the
tiger cubs. Later, after
four years, he had his first disciple, and
he became the Buddha in
this world.
And in the year of his first disciple, the
first person, the first person, the first
disciple, he taught
it about the Four Noble Truths, repeating it.  Three times, and
they saw the non-direction,
they saw the non-existence. Because of that
mental connection with both the
Buddha and the tiger, it's called
cavena. That story is the
first teaching that the Buddha ever
gave, ever preached. He didn't
translate it immediately after enlightenment, but waited
a week because he thought no one
would understand it.
But you, when you teach
more and more, I hope you
will learn. When you
teach more and more,
you will have that experience, just
like the student who didn't understand
anything. No one understood anything. But, but we keep going,
we keep
going.
The Buddha, after the day of enlightenment,
waited
day after day, surely to help
people in some way, and he refused to
teach for a few weeks, then
after 5 days, he said that maybe some
people could easily understand something. Then he
started preaching. That's the story
about the tiger. It
was before I had those
recordings, but
in  24 days of teaching, when
this book was recorded, he taught
this story in detail,
how he did it in 24 days, I don't know,
maybe they didn't have a break here.
Next, there's the next part,
our teacher is the Buddha, the
one with Mahacarena, with boundless compassion,
this is how he
became a Buddha. Then there's Sana, the king who studied
there, we studied in Kyoto, all of it
is the Buddha's image,
meaning
you should say
that you yourself, the
doctor, is just your own self, and that
means nothing else. Sam means
we think about ourselves, focusing on
what we want to hear. The program
with people who only focus on
what they want, these things
will be difficult. If
your habit is to take
care of yourself first, then
things like giving your body away will be very
difficult.
But what
is a year?
You
can always add levels when you
do the retreat.  This week you
can hear this story about people
I wouldn't call "Body Donors,"
but rather about sharing the bodies they
possess. I don't want you to think
that King Shiseiena
gave someone else their body—
that's not the point, and that's
not why they cut off
exactly half of someone's body.
He didn't offer someone's leg to a
poor person. They realized
that other people have the right to
50% of another person's body, the right to 50% of their body—
an equal right,
and it extends to your money,
your time, and your body.
It's a sign that other people
also have the same rights, equal rights,
with your time, money, and attention. It's
very important that you don't
see someone giving away their hand or leg,
but someone giving away 50% of
their body because
they understood that their body
has the same right, the same right, equal rights
to other people's bodies. I do
conduct meditation retreats.  Three years on that mountain, in
that valley next to it. There was nothing there, never before
had anyone
lived there, and the animals there were
very strange, the
insects very strange.
We had one, there were things
like
moths flying around like this,
but
there was a silver lightning bolt there,
where you see all the
old people. They were shooting at each other there
because they had sovereignty. This is
your silver mine, this is your silver mine.
Why are they near the cabin,
the part of my retreat, the line, it's
very important, that line,
it's very important.
Where will I stop? Where will you start?
And what they said is,
even when you are meditating this week, there
's no way you can
happily cut your body in half
and do that,
but you can pray for the day.
You see, you can pray for
that day, and there's something
called
attention, so try to...  To
get his attention, my teacher
told me a story about a
man who, in the 1950s,
went to Diamond Mountain to meditate,
giving up all
his business.
My teacher taught us about a
young man who, for the class,
packed up all his things and
went through town
to a small forest,
about a few hundred hectares in New Jersey, in
the middle of the highway, and lived in the
middle of that forest because he heard
the story of the Maragraya.
My teacher said, "Let
him go, he'll come back in
three days." It took two days,
and he came back. People said, "It's
too difficult, it's too cold." My teacher said, "Yeah,
meditating indoors is better, right?"
Don't do
all that. The Buddha cut
his body
in half, cut off a few of
his fingers. It's not the way, it's
not like that.
I'm trying to do something,
you guys should do it slowly but steadily.
The point here is that we don't do
grandiose things to get everyone's attention or
to make people think. Here, we
do it quietly, sharing
ourselves with others.
And people are the best people;
they do it invisibly. You do
n't know they're doing it. My wife is
a perfect example.
Just this week,
just pray that you can
reach a point where you truly
realize that others have
equal rights to your time and
attention.
Then gradually you begin to adapt to
their rights.
Don't try to do it all in one
day; it won't work. Do it
slowly, slowly again. You
must expand
your energy, you must use emptiness.
Otherwise, you cannot
serve all beings if you understand
emptiness. If you see emptiness
directly, you personally can
influence all beings.
This universe is a direct, face-to-face encounter;
don't try to reach
that point, you're just being foolish. There will
come a day when you can serve
all beings directly at
once, and that's what we're
going to. But you have to
see emptiness to be
able to do that.
People say, "Oh, I don't
want to learn about emptiness. I want to learn about
compassion."
It's compassion; you can't be compassionate. There's a
teacher pointing out a
creature outside, something on its
head.
It's going around, circling inside
families with about 15
little ones.
I don't know what it has on its head.
This is a picture of a tiger with tiger cubs.
Think about it sometimes this week
when you're kind. There
will come a time when you're good at learning emptiness. If you learn emptiness well,
you can adapt to
everyone equally at
once, and you have no limits.
Instead of going crazy trying to
adapt to 10 people at once...  Perhaps
you're limited, try doing something
in a different direction. There are millions of
bodies, and try to adapt.
Try working with three people; it's
much easier and more sustainable.
Don't try it with just one body.
You can't serve,
you can't restore more than
a few people. But
pray more. The idea here is,
this week, think about the
story of Richena. If you don't
have this story, I think the
heart can give you
this story. I've translated the whole
story and made it free for
you on
DiamondTatterBread.com.
Sorry, on the Asia platform, there will
be that story, and you can read
it and say, "I want to be
able to do that." That's enough. And try to be
wise and perceptive, remembering that
others have equal rights to
happiness, and
there
's a translation of that part. They
have the same rights to
your time as you do. You should...  Think about
it, think about it, and cook it for
a while, and you'll clean it up
because it will make you
happy because you're doing what
you know you have to do in
this world. Why did you come to
this world? We call it
meditation in Kyoto
with a group of CSP business people in
China, and it's called mushroom meditation, straw mushroom
meditation, and
it talks about the darkness because
straw mushrooms grow in the darkness. The
darkness means where you are, where you are.
Before coming to time, where will you
go after this world?
And this darkness is longer than the
light. You have a certain amount of time
between those two darknesses, but
there is a very large darkness of
the past and a very
large darkness of the future. And you only have
this short time
in between the lines to be in the light
to do something, do something with
your life, and
you will run out of time.
Time will run out.  It doesn't matter how
much yoga you do, how
much green banana drink you drink, time
is limited,
time will run out. Do something
good, do something good with it. Be
rolled, try,
try to
serve the needs. When it serves,
your immediate demands are endless,
they will run out. You can't satisfy all
your needs.
Later, you have no choice
between the straw mushrooms, between the straw mushrooms,
between the darkness. Before you arrive
here, it
's over. When you leave here, oh, where will you
go?
You won't be here that long. You won't
miss out on so much.
Why not make more people
happy? It's logical, right?
He has another comment for
you, and we will start together.
This person,
Baba. Meaning, it makes sense to take care
of others. Please, Baba, have
the
joy or the
sweet thought about making
others want what they want more than what
you want.
He said,
you know? If you  Think about it,
it's logical,
it's logical that
you should take care of other people,
not just yourself, it's simple
logic. And he said, why I'll say,
we'll say it to people in the
community. Meaning, for example,
when it's in the
community, it means the feeling, the
feeling when you're planting before your
husband chooses, when we go through San
Diego, we go through a field,
that way, that field used to be very close
to the coffee plantation.  Now you have to drive for
an hour to see Phoenix
and
the people are
like your fields. If
you want to plant orchids,
they are clearing some of the land
here. Do you see
what they are doing? But they will try to
plant
orchids in the desert. This is a
foreign company
and they have cleared the land here,
leveling it and it's very boring. The teacher
posted a company here. You need
a sweet, open
land, a piece of land for the husband to
choose. We need to have a
lot of free time and we can
prepare our garden. You
can walk past 10 or 15 steps, but
it takes about 2 weeks to
prepare for the next season. Summer
takes 2 weeks to prepare the land.
Think about the land like that, prepare the land well,
then on the day
we give it to the people. Kim Ngoc.
The whole story of Lee Jong,
ancient 8,
has a description of the wish gem,
and this is the gem you
find in the stream, for example, and there is
a gem there.  The ritual involves washing it,
placing it in a silk cloth at
a certain distance from the moon,
hanging it, and offering a
special prayer. It
becomes Aladdin's lamp, giving you
whatever you want. It's called the
center of money. Who is the center of money,
and who is the field of
others? Others
are your ticket to success.
Others can give you everything
you want.
Others are like a field of gold,
a good field, or like
a gem that will give you
whatever you want. There's a lamp, the
story of Aladdin's lamp that I
learned in high school,
which I wouldn't teach to
women. If you ever told Veronica, "
I teach you,"
I would cut off your body. There's
an idea that
whatever you want in
your life, you can have it, but
you have to choose the lamp.
You have to take care of
others, and all that...  What you want, you
will have, and I personally can say I'm
not the best at doing
that, but I've tried to do some, and
it's made my life feel like
a miracle.
Every aspect of my life
is a miracle—everything—my
finances, my friends,
my work, everything about me is
incredibly outstanding. If you just do
a little bit of the idea of
equality, this equal rights,
focus this week, and the idea
that other people have the right
to have happiness, the power to be
happy, the result
of that mindset is
incredibly outstanding, like
it's very strange, very strange.
You will have a happy, joyful life.
I'm not too worried about happiness,
but I want to have joy.
When someone promises you
happiness, it's a little bit boring,
but it's joy, joy, it has to be joy, joy,
if you have the right, you have it, it's very
joyful, it's very joyful, and your whole life...
You will be very provocative.
He said, "Look,
even if it's
not about spirituality,
you have everything you
can in life through
other people. Yesterday, those
other people served you all day,
regardless of what you have. It's
not just about simply
sitting here. It comes from
other people.
You
are simply returning to them
what they have given you. Because you see here
the clothes you are wearing. Now you are wearing
the green drink, not the
delicious drink
you drank this morning, it
comes from other people. In the
book of Dependent Origination, the
book of about 500 pages by the monk,
he said
there is Dependent Origination here. What? What?
There are other people giving you
everything, giving you everything.
Forget about compassion and
forget about trying not to be selfish.
You have already nurtured
others. Why did you have breakfast?
And because you are wearing underwear now,
underwear. Now
I hope
some people
have to
light the oil for someone."  It takes a lot of
work to get what you
're wearing now. Forget about equality. You owe something.
You have a debt, you owe something. You owe someone
for having breakfast, for drinking
that green drink, for
wearing those clothes.
You owe someone,
and by the way,
you owe people like your mother.
I don't know, looking at my face, I guess
I'm 78, from 70. I
just realized that the decision to
have a baby is unbelievable.
Now when I look at her, I realize
you're talking about 20 years, right? 20
years of
investment, I mean all your attention.
I'm giving up on having to
work with people like that. It
's a baby, it's about a baby,
not to be honest, it's serious.
Someone in your life, their
whole time and
their money, they ask to sacrifice
their life's priorities, and the
woman
gives her whole body, regardless of what
your body is like.  Before
and after you have children, you are
giving your body the
child, and your body becomes a
milk factory intentionally.
You have a purpose, and you are happy
doing that. It's very, very much like
giving up 20 years of your life and
giving up your body.
Not only,
not just people who did
this in your
past lives, but all the people you've
met, all the people you've ever met,
have given up their lives for you to
take care of you.
My wife said yesterday something very
nonsensical, something like, "
Someone told me to get pregnant again,
4 or 5 children already,"
and my wife said, "Oh, she just
wants to be happy, happy," and
I said, "What?" and she said, "
Having children is the happiest thing that
will ever happen to you," and my wife has
two children, and I said, "What?
Having another baby? Because that's the
best thing you can do."  The author
here,
everyone you meet has been
your mother,
even
here, it's a bit tricky, the Tibetan word, I
tried,
I once had 3 weeks, I tried, I
took a year-long class on
Bodhisattva practice, I tried, I
got accepted into that class, there were 3
lamas who would say if I
had enough qualities to learn,
if my Tibetan was enough to be
able to take that class for a year, it was in the
Himalayas,
and I, oh, I could pass, I couldn't
pass, I only knew five words,
and the teacher saw me and said, 'Just come, come and
do the test,' and I said, 'Okay,' it was
one thing, and I sat down in the
middle of the panel, those are
very big lamas, he is the one who
teaches Vasaki yogie, the
saying, I sat down and those 3
lamas, oh my god, this is going to be
terrible. And he said to me, 'I will accept
this student, I will accept this student,' '
Okay, I will ask you the
Tibetan word and tell me.'  I know that
if you know and I say okay,
you are truly hopeless one
day. This word... oh,
I...
mother...
I have brothers... I told you... you... you... you... you... you... oh, it
means mother...
but there are two... there are two mothers... two mothers... the
property is not your mother... look three... it
means they are not your mother.
He said, look,
you have a responsibility to
treat all other people equally. They
have been your mother countless times. You
owe them, and that day... even a mother...
even when they come to their mother...
your mother... you still owe them... it
means
taking care of other people's needs,
like giving them clothes, giving them food,
or cleaning up their messes like a garbage truck. A
child pays them, they pay them,
another still does the same.
The cost of having a
child keeps going, it keeps increasing week
by week, but that day... he said, look,
everyone has been your mother
countless times. Even now,
when there are 8 billion people around, there are only...
One person is your mother, but the
others take care of your mother and take care
of you all the time.
Because now you're wearing clothes and
this morning you had food, and
they still take care of you.
Forget about it, forget about your past life or your
past. You don't need to think about
things like that. You owe everything
you have right now,
and you owe it continuously. You
will keep
owing it to others, to ordinary people.
Forget about your past life or
the people
related to your mother. Here it's very interesting,
for example, Samba milk,
Tibetan milk. Now you can
buy the best Tibetan milk on Amazon.
I don't know which company it is, but
I've tried them all,
but it means a small bag
in their bell, they carry a
small bag, the blisters in Tibet,
it takes about three spoonfuls, the
spoon is like the kind of barley flower
and Anna's
breakfast, and no small bag
with me, and if  It takes
about 3 minutes, then they mix it with water
and eat it with their hands. It's
very sweet, it's delicious.
You have to wash your hands beforehand. That's why
he said just a little bit of barley,
that grain, if you have a
life, it's very useful. I
use it all the time. My wife also learned how to cook it.
It's
food that's ground and
milled.
Regardless of what you have for
breakfast this morning, first
someone sowed and planted the field. When
you
drive to the Arizona Open, you
see what life is like working in the
fields. It's very hard, it
's a very simple life. I
worked in the fields for a few years during
my college days. It was
extremely hard,
and it exhausts you. In
kindergarten, for a few years, some people
created food for you. Someone
planted it, and you may have machinery,
etc. But it
's a very,
extremely hard job, very difficult, very exhausting, very
tough.  It's intense, then whoever digs
has to water those fields, and
that's also a very hard job.
It's a funny word,
up in the village, up in the village, on the road, up in the
village, you see people
going out into the bushes, running to your car and
throwing grass on the road, and you
drive up to it.
And it will separate the grass to the sides.
Then they try to clear
the shelf, the grass before the car
comes, and it's very dangerous. Helping
the father means that in the old days, they
used to let the
cows stay in the...
someone used to do that, someone
prepared barley or grain
for you to eat. Cloud hair, Sanskrit,
20 dollars, 25 dollars,
superstitions,
tank
means
immeasurable,
amitabha
[music],
put in your feet, and the clothes
you wear now, if you've ever been
to a shop in Hong Kong or something,
you know, it's impossible, impossible.
Imagine
someone in Bangladesh
sewing clothes for you. Someone has to do
that. And it's a cruel job,
and people
even die in the factory. You
're wearing those clothes, and someone has to put
shoes on you.
[music]
Because maybe your body is a living thing.
By the surface, you wear clothes and you
eat,
and they deserve half of your body, a
part of your body, because they
made it, and they make your body
warm. So why are you thick? And they
've invested in your body. Then
we'll do another exercise. Do
a sentence,
two people.
[music]
The place where you're sitting right now,
and tell me which house or apartment or
temple you're sitting in,
it's training, it
's a short form, and above is the hour. It's the
kindness of others.
Pani is the kindness of others.
By the way, the book Cartreem
is about how yoga works, it was just
published in Ukraine, and I want to
thank Rosa
now.  It's in both Russia and
Ukraine, and the publisher is in Russia,
and the publisher in Ukraine is also about to release it.
This book is being sold in Ukraine for
$1.99. You
can get that book if
you're in Ukraine.
Buy a few
copies. Someone is
sitting here. There are so
many people and so many
animals here. Someone
laid the
land to build a house,
someone built the walls,
someone
chopped wood,
mixed the water and cement,
etc. It's
not just the clothes you're wearing,
not just the breakfast you ate
this morning. But if you're sitting here and
you have a road, you
owe someone something.
And that would be the house you're
living in. But this temple was built
by hand in the first century. Here, and
I remember a
woman, 75-80 years old. She carried
each brick and laid them
here, everyone.
Sitting here, you already owe the
first generation if you go to the
cabins that were built and they paid for
the 3-year retreat, each
person paid for their own house and
built it with their own hands,
mostly the cabin. If you've ever
met them, you should thank them for
giving up all their money. They built the
house with their own hands and they
provided their money. You already own it, you already owe
others if you are living
in a house someone built it for
you,
and it's an extremely cruel job.
I did it on my page, it's
hard work someone did for
my cafe, and it's extremely
difficult and a very difficult and dangerous job.
It's very difficult.
Then he said, "
Look, for a monk, it's a
scarf, it's like a
sleeping bag for Buddhist monks.
It's a
long piece of clothing that you can wear to wrap
yourself and sleep under a tree. It's
a tradition, and now it..."  It's
like a ceremony
in a monastery; there's someone who
goes around to make sure you're
wearing it. If you're not, they'll beat you. If
you're not,
it's hot, it's hot.
Every monk, every nun, and every
novice has a robe like
that. If you're smart, you
'll make one very thin because it's very
hot.
In Tibet,
wool is cheaper than cotton because
they can't grow cotton there,
and there are a lot of sheep. So, the Master
said, "There are a
lot of sheep's wool. Someone has to shear the sheep's wool,
someone has to weave it into pants,
someone has to
sew it into clothes, someone has to sew
it into fabric for us to wear."
Meaning, we'll wear it, we'll be ready to wear
it. This is ready, ready, ready, ready.
The Master is talking about the pants, the pants, the
shirt. So, you already have it. You owe
someone else the
simplest piece of clothing
you're wearing. Right now, I'm saying, "
First time always, underwear, the simplest piece of clothing
that everyone has."  In
this world right now, it
requires a lot of work to
create it, to distribute it, to put it
in stores for you to
wash, and so on. All
those things...
we'll be
a little gentle here,
and I want you to practice it today. We've
talked about Zen, the Right to Equality,
and we'll review the
chapter about the interaction with
the person you met last week and what they
want. What do you want? What do they want? Can you do
it better? You don't
necessarily have to have an
argument, but you can do
it better.
Can you respect their rights,
their equal rights? And then the
question arises: do they have
equal rights with you in terms of
your time? We always
agree that they have equal rights
with their time.
Veronica can dedicate time
whenever you want. I will dedicate time whenever
I want.  Whether
or not that's possible is a question, but
now it's more complicated. Do they have the
right to your time?
Because of your clothes, because of your
breakfast, because of where you're sitting in your
house this morning, perhaps they have more
rights over you than you think. It's
a meditation we're going to do.
Can you approach
other people with the idea that you
have equal rights to
their time, that they have equal rights
to your time? The Buddha
said that,
right? And now we're going to do
another meditation. And this is
one we do in DCI,
we call it the croissant meditation.
Take something very simple
in your room, like you
have a piece of bread, or a
glass of water, or you eat a piece of fruit. There's a
lot of work involved in making it.
Take something that you ate morning and evening,
something that you ate,
and then trace it, trace it.
Recall who brought the room to
you, who bought it from the store,
who put it in the store, who
moved it to the store, who built
the highway, who moved it, who moved the ship,
who moved the car, who planted the tree,
who
watered the tree. Look at the people
working in these countries; it's an
extremely difficult job. A
simple fruit will be your meditation
today. We will take a
fruit and trace it back, tracing it
backward. Then we will go deeper, there is
a meditation, a
very beautiful meditation.
You will perform this Recall meditation.
First, we will
meditate on a physical object,
like the fruit you ate
today. When you do this
meditation, you
will meditate on
a fruit, a
piece of it, a piece of clothing,
many things. It's an imagination: someone
brought it to the store, or someone brought it
to my cabin, or someone else.  I planted
it,
and then I want you to take that fruit
because the person who planted it
used life
from the tree they planted, and someone
held that seed, and many
years ago, the fruit you are eating
is the result of
50,000 years of teamwork. That
silly banana or that
apple you eat
at the diamond mountain in this generation, it
's the result of a lot of work
done for you, but someone
planted that original seed from
50,000 people. That's the work of
50,000, 50,000 years for you to get
that apple.
Because from
that person's time, people brought the
seed and brought the wings to
the field to bring the fruit back to
you. It's not just last year, but for the
past 50,000 years, people have done the work.
I once had 1.5 administrative staff working
for me in the coffee shop.  Reviewing
hundreds of administrative tasks and paperwork,
you have 50,000 years of paperwork, just
like you have jobs.
Those people who do paperwork for
you for 50,000 years, you should trace back, trace
back, we will do it together. Now
we will practice
gratitude meditation, then we will go
deeper into this meditation, this meditation has
two parts, are you ready?
We will start with 20 breaths
a day, I want you to meditate in 7 steps
Ultra. If you don't know, you have
an account,
take
another fruit, a good fruit, and cook
diamond. This morning we have a
green drink, a glass of fruit juice,
choose something,
fruit, rice, bread, whatever.
Whoever brought it to your house or to the
temple here,
let's  Thank them, or try to picture what they
look like
afterward. Imagine where they brought it from,
maybe from a store, and try to
picture everyone
working to help put that item on the
shelf for you. They work hard all
day;
someone
takes your money;
someone created the money; someone created
credit cards; someone programmed online payments;
hundreds of people
maintain that system;
someone brings
the produce from the farm to the store. I
used to work on a truck in
college, and it was a very hard job.
Someone harvested
the vegetables and fruits; someone picked them and
packaged them for you—it was incredibly hard work.
Someone watered the fields; someone
fertilized; someone tilled the land;
someone cleared the land. We
owe them our time and
our bodies. They have rights to a portion of our
time. They have some rights
to what we do with our bodies.
The thought of thanking them,
the thought that they have rights
to a portion of my time, some portion of my
time—it also has a schedule.
And this is meditation number 2 that I want
you to do today.
This idea is to
think about the
idea that other people perhaps have
an equal right to time, a
part of my time, some of
my time. How did that idea begin? So what is the
lineage of that idea? Oh,
I heard it in Lambin,
and I want you to
trace it back mentally,
not physically. The thought
that led you
to this point,
your mind
is considering today
the potential, the possibility that
other people have a right to
time, and you, we, owe them
some of our time. If we
respect the idea that
other people have rights, that everyone has
certain rights in this world,
then those people have a right to
some of your time because they are
taking care of you, they are giving you
their time, and they are making you
clothes, and they are building your house. And
where did this idea come from? In the
beginning,
who said they had it?  equality,
why am I hearing it now? Oh,
I heard it in Lam Rim. Okay,
so you had a thought, right?
I want to
hear. I'm... I want to hear more about
that.
What did you think of before? What is that?
I'm curious. I'm looking around.
I feel
it's a step forward that I can make
in my life. I hear about
things related to Buddhism.
These things that interest...
where did the thought come from? Oh, I guess
when I was in college I
heard about it. I did
n't study it, but I knew about it right away
and I was thinking about it.
What happened before? I
thought I was going to college.
I had...
what happened? It
came from my family
when I was thinking my mom and my mom
talked about going to college. And
then those thoughts... It's one
and I remember... I think
about history, about the rest of the
world in my High School...
I can remember those thoughts, I
can remember those thoughts to the
first classes.  First, at school,
I can
especially remember the things I did wrong at
school. I remember how I felt.
I remember being curious about
books, people, and what they
taught. I remember the first day
before I went to school,
and I remember what it was like with my mother, with my
father, with my family.
I remember the things
we talked about, the thoughts
I had when I was young, the things in
my mind. I remember the day
in my cradle, touching the blanket and
feeling how soft it was. I
was captivated by that softness. I
remember thinking about that softness.
I want you to do
another meditation
today. First, material things.
Choose something you ate, something
you wore, something you drank,
the house you lived in, and trace
back to the people who created those
material things, the
people who passed on the
knowledge about building houses from 50,000.
last year. And thank them. Go back and
find reasons to thank more people.
Gratitude is
an exercise that creates healthy happiness,
and then I want you to realize
in the second test, and this
should be your Fresh Time.
If you do the retreat,
you have the
bright time and the dark time in the day,
the bright time.